Register of the Charles Maynard Cooke papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1928-1964 (Boxes 1-9)
  - President's Board of Consultants on Foreign Intelligence Activities; Brigadier General John F. Cassidy, 1957
  - Prouty, Senator Winston L., 1962
  - Purnell, Captain W. R. (Speck), 1933, 1938
  - Putman, Charles E., 1964
  - Putnam, Abby, 1945
  - Pye, Admiral W. S.; U.S. Naval War College, 1943
  - Pyroil Company, 1937
  - Quinn, Major General William W., 1960
  - Radford, Admiral Arthur W., 1953-1955, 1958-1959
  - Raguet, Commander E. C. (Ed), 1934-1935
  - Ramsey, D. C., 1937, 1946
  - Randolph, John, 1935, 1936
  - Ransom, Mollie (Mrs. P. C.), 1934
  - Read, Commander O. M. (Monk), 1931-1932
  - Reader's Digest, 1941, 1949-1950
  - Rees, W. L., 1948
  - Reichmuth, Rear Admiral F. L. (Dutch), 1936, 1942
  - Reifsnider, Rear Admiral L. F., 1948
  - Reinicke, Commander F. G. (Red), 1936
  - Reinider, Rex, 1948
  - Reynolds, Elizabeth, 1937
  - Rhee, Syngman, President of the Republic of South Korea, 1955
  - Rice, Mr. L. P., 1934
  - Richardson, Admiral James O., 1935-1937, 1939
  - Rivers, Congressman L. Mendel, 1963
  - Roach, J. T., 1940
  - Robertson, Assistant Secretary of State Walter, 1954, 1958-1959
  - Robinson, Senator Joe T.; Pearl Hendricks, 1930
  - Robinson, S. M.; Webb Institute of Naval Architecture, 1948
  - Rodgers, James L. (Ducky), 1936-1937
  - Rogers, Lieutenant Commander Edward B., 1937
  - Rood, George A., 1935-1936, 1948
  - Roosevelt, Nicholas; New York Times, 1944
  - Roper, Captain Clifford H. (Stony), 1942
  - Rosendahl, Captain C. E., 1942
  - Rossell, Henry E. (Moose), 1930, 1948
  - Roswall, Lieutenant Commander Paul E., 1937
  - Rothwell, C. Easton, 1960
  - Rowley, Lieutenant Commander Welton, 1942
  - Royce, Don, 1948
  - Rupertus, Lieutenant Colonel W. H., 1937
  - Rutter, Commander J. B., 1936
  - Sabel, Captain F. L.; Chinese Maritime Customs, 1947-1948 (Box 8)
  - Sabin, Captain L. S., 1946-1947
  - Salisbury, Stanton W., 1944, 1948
  - San Francisco Chronicle; Paul C. Smith, 1948
  - San Francisco Council of Republican Women; Vere de Vere Adams Hutchins (Mrs. Robert B.), 1956
  - Santa Fe Railroad (Long Beach, Ca.), 1937
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1948, 1958-1959
  - Saurette, Lieutanant J. O. (Joe), 1934-1935
  - Scandland, Captain Francis W., 1936-1937
  - Schlichtiger, J. H., 1947
  - Schuyler, Franklin J., 1932
  - Scoville, Lieutenant Commander J. A., 1936
  - Scudder, Congressman Hubert B., 1949
  - Seattle, Washington. Chamber of Commerce, 1937
  - Severt, R. W., 1951
  - Seyfried, Lieutenant Commander J. H., 1938
  - Sharp, Captain Alexander (Sandy), 1937, 1948
  - Sharpe, Norvelle, W., 1937
  - Shaw, James, 1950
  - Sheaffer (W. A.) Pen Co., 1936
  - Sheehan, Jerry, 1936-1937
  - Shen, Chang-huan; Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Republic of China, 1954
  - Sherman, Captain Frederick C. (Ted), 1937, 1942
  - Sherman, Fannie (Mrs. Frederick C.), 1942
  - Sherman, Admiral Forrest P., 1946, 1950
  - Shih, Chao-ying; Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Republic of China, 1950
  - Simons, Commander R. B. (Bentham, Bill), 1942
  - Sims, Admiral William S., 1934
  - Smeallie, Captain John M., 1932
  - Smedberg, Vice Admiral William R. (Smeddy), 1946, 1963
  - Smellow, Lieutenant Morris, 1936-1937
  - Smith, John J., 1958
  - Smith, Admiral W. W. (Poco), undated
  - Smith News Company (San Francisco, Ca.), 1951
  - Snyder, Rear Admiral C. P.; U.S. Naval War College, 1937
  - Sokolsky, George, 1959
  - Soong, Ching Ling (Madame Sun Yat-sen), 1946
  - Soong, Laura (Mrs. T. V.), undated
  - Soong, Stassen Y. C., 1959
  - Soong, T. V., 1946
  - Sourwine, J. G., 1959
  - Sparkman, Senator John J., 1951
  - Spears, Captain W. O., 1936
  - Spiller, Rufe, 1949
  - Spivak, Lawrence E., 1962
  - Sprague, Rear Admiral Thomas L., 1947-1948
  - Spruance, Raymond, 1948
  - Stakemiller, Mr., 1936
  - Standard Oil Company of New Jersey (Washington, D.C.), 1930
  - Stark, Admiral Harold R., 1941-1942, 1947-1949, 1951
    With letter from Dwight Eisenhower to Stark attached.
  - Steel, A. T.; New York Herald-Tribune, 1946-1947
  - Steele, Captain J. M., 1948
  - Stewart, Captain G. V., 1937
  - Stone, Rear Admiral Ellery W., 1944-1945
  - Stone, Captain Ellis S., 1934, 1936-1937, 1942, undated
  - Strausz-Hupé, Robert, 1945
  - Stuart, Marie (Mrs. Harry A.), 1942-1943, 1946
  - Stuart, Ambassador (to China) J. Leighton, 1947-1948
  - Sulzberger, Mrs. Iphigene Ochs, 1944
  - Sun, General Li-jen, 1952
  - Swanson, Rear Admiral C. A., 1947
  - Swenson, Lieutenant Commander Lyman K., 1937
  - Taft, Senator Robert, 1951
  - Tan, Koh Choh; Chung Shing Jit Pao, Ltd., 1952
  - Tang, Ka Ting, 1946
  - Taylor, Roger C.; U.S. Naval Institute, 1963(?)
  - Theiss, Commander Paul S., 1939
  - Thomas, Dorsey O., 1948, 1964
  - Thompson, Edith, 1940-1941
  - Thompson, H. Keith, 1946-1947
  - Thurber, H. R., 1948
  - Tisdale, Commander Mahlon S., 1936
  - Todd, Captain Ford A., 1934-1935, 1937
  - Townsend, George H., and Ford, Ellsworth (Lank), 1936
  - Train, Captain Harold C., 1937-1938, 1942
  - Trammell, Niles; National Broadcasting Company, 1944
  - Truman, President Harry, 1945
  - Trump, H. R., 1937
  - Tsen, Captain T. C., Republic of China, 1956-1957
  - Tsiang, Tingfu F., 1951
  - Tso, Chang-chin; Chinese Customs Service, 1948
  - Tu, Hoh, 1958-1959
  - Union Pacific Railroad Co. (Los Angeles, Ca.), 1937 (Box 9)
  - United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia; Arthur L. Carson, 1956
  - U.S. Army. Office of the Chief of Military History, 1959-1960
  - U.S. Comptroller General, 1938-1939
  - U.S. Consulate, Santiago, Cuba; William P. Blocker, 1936
  - U.S. Consulate General, Shanghai, China; Paul W. Meyer, 1947
  - U.S. Consulate General, Taipei, Taiwan; Robert C. Strong, 1950
  - U.S. Department of Justice, Immigration and Naturalization Service; Bruce G. Barber, 1956
  - U.S. Embassy, Taipei, Taiwan; K. L. Rankin, 1953
  - U.S. Naval Academy. Alumni Association, undated
  - U.S. Naval Academy. Navy Athletic Association, 1936
  - U.S. Naval Air Station, Anacostia, D.C., Ship's Service Store, 1936-1937
  - U.S. Naval Institute, 1938-1941, 1954, 1960
  - U.S. Naval Research Laboratory, Anacostia, D.C., 1932, 1937
  - U.S. Navy. Bureau of Navigation, Library; Isabel Dubois, 1931
  - U.S. Navy. Bureau of Supplies and Accounts, Special Payments Division, 1933, 1950
  - U.S. Navy. Eleventh Naval District Library, 1937
  - U.S. Navy. Hydrographic Office, 1934, 1936
  - U.S. Senate. Internal Security Subcommittee; Senator McCarran, 1951
  - U.S. Treasury Department. Bureau of Customs, 1936
  - Upham, Rear Admiral F. B., undated
  - Van de Carr, Commander James C., 1935-1937
  - Wall, Jimmie G., 1948
  - Waltham Watch Company, 1932
  - Wang, General Shu-ming, Republic of China, 1957-1958
  - Ware, Commander James G., 1937-1938, 1942
  - Warlick, Lieutenant Commander William W. (Walter), 1937, 1948
  - Warner, Rawleigh, 1948
  - Warren, Governor Earl, 1950
  - Wedemeyer, General Albert C., 1944, 1949-1950, 1953, 1959-1962
  - Wei, Captain C. M., China, 1947
  - Welker, Lieutenant Commander George W., 1936-1937
  - Welch, Robert; John Birch Society, 1959
  - Wellbrock, Commander J. H. (Jack), 1937
  - Wheeler, C. Julian, 1942, 1963
  - Wheeler, Doanda (Mrs. Julian), 1960
  - White, Captain R. A., 1936
  - Whitney, W. L., 1934
  - Wilkens (John H.) Company (Los Angeles, Ca.), 1937
  - William, Maurice; American China Policy Association, undated
  - Willoughby, Major General C. A.; Foreign Intelligence Digest, 196-
  - Willson, Russell, 1948
  - Wilson, A. Vincent, 1953-1954
  - Wiltse, Commander L. J., 1937
  - Wingo, Congressman Otis, 1930
  - Woods, Captain J. S., 1938
  - Woods, Lieutenant Colonel S. A. (Sam), 1937-1938
  - World Affairs Council of Northern California; Monroe E. Deutsch, 1950
  - Wortman, Captain Ward K., 1931
  - Worden, Lieutenant Commander Frank L., 1937
  - Wright, Commander C. H., 1937-1938
  - Wu, Shih-chi, 1953, 1955
  - Wylie, Evan M., undated
  - Wynkoop, Rear Admiral T. P. (Tom), 1948
  - Yang, Lieutenant Hsi-han, Republic of China, 1954, 1961
  - Yang, Paishen (Lieutenant Colonel Sammy Young) Republic of China, 1954-1955
  - Yeh, George K. C., Minister of Foreign Affairs, Republic of China, 1950-1954, 1956-1957, 1960-1961, 1963
  - Yen, C. K., Minister of Finance, Republic of China, 1960-1961
  - Yin, K. Y., 1951
  - Yik, Chen Yeh, 1952
  - Young Americans for Freedom, Bay Area Association; James Ashley, 1961
  - Yu, James, Chinese Ambassador to Italy, 1954
  - Yu, Ta-wei, Minister of Defense, Republic of China, 1951, 1953, 1955, 1957, 1960
  - Zacharias, Commander E. M., 1934-1935
  - Zemke, Captain Eric, 1932-1933, 1948, 1960
  - Ziroli, Lieutenant Commander Humbert W. (Tony), 1931
  - Miscellaneous
- LOG BOOKS, DIARY, AND NOTEBOOKS, circa 1931-1954 (Box 10)
  Log entries of air flights made by Cooke, 1931-1948; typewritten diary, 1946; and holograph appointment and address notations.
  - Aviators Flight Log Book, 1931-1945
  - Aviators Flight Log Book, 1945-1948
  - Diary, 1946 January-May
  - Notebooks (3), undated
  - Address book
- SPEECHES, WRITINGS, AND INTERVIEWS, 1931-1964 (Boxes 11-15)
  Holograph, typescript, carbon, mimeograph, and printed copies of speeches, radio broadcasts, articles, essays, reviews, public statements, congressional testimony, reports, and interviews, and accompanying correspondence, notes, and news clippings, arranged alphabetically by title, or form in cases where no title is available, with page length of the most complete draft or copy.
  - "Admiral King's Return to Active Command in 1940 at the Age of 62," typescript drafts with carbon copies, undated; 3 pages. (Box 11)
  - "The Army's Need for Big Carriers and a Marine Corps," typescript drafts with carbon copies, undated; 9 pages.
  - "Background of Our Strategy in the Second World War," typescript draft (incomplete), undated; 5 pages.
  - "The Battle of Taiwan," published as a newspaper article, typescript drafts and printed copies, 1950 March 5, April 16; 4 pages.
  - "Bombing North Korean Towns," carbon copies of typescript draft, undated; 2 pages.
  - "Buck Peters Cleans Up the Town," typescript draft with carbon copy, circa 1932 or 1933; 17 pages.
  - "Casablanca Conference," typescript drafts with carbon copies, undated; 6 pages.
  - "The Coming Communist Leadership," typescript draft and carbon copies of another typescript draft, 1946 June; 9 pages.
  - "Comments on Draft of Manuscript 'U.S. Army in World War II, The War in the Pacific, Strategy and Command: Turning the Tide, 1941-1943' by Louis Morton," carbon copy of typescript and photocopies with letter addressed to the Department of the Army, Office of the Chief of Military History, 1959 August 14; 38 pages plus enclosures.
  - "Creative Authority," typescript draft, 1959 April-May; 17 pages.
  - "The Development and Use of the Armed Forces," typescript draft, 1958 April 11; 3 pages.
  - "Far East and Where to Go From Here," remarks made before the Camp Pendleton Monthly Officers' Seminar, carbon copies of typewritten transcript, circa 1954-1955; 23 pages.
  - "Fitness Records and Selection for Promotion," United States Naval Institute Proceedings, Vol. 57, 647-652, reprints, 1931 May; 6 pages.
  - "The Foreign Policy Survey Board," proposal submitted to President's Consultants Commission on International Intelligence Activities, carbon copies of typescript drafts, 1956; 5 pages.
  - "Forty-Two Years in the Navy," typescript draft, undated; 10 pages.
  - "Growth and Genesis of Freedom," typescript draft, undated; 5 pages.
  - "How Formosa Was Dropped But Did Not Fall," typescript draft with carbon copy, circa 1952-1953; 8 pages.
  - "Importance of Quemoy to World Communism," speech delivered before the Commonwealth Club of California, San Francisco, California, carbon copy of typewritten transcript, printed transcript, and printed copy reproduced in Vital Speeches, 1958 September 26, October 15; 11 pages.
  - "Indo China - Laos," carbon copy of typescript draft, undated; 4 pages.
  - Interview with Cooke by John Osborne, Sonoma, California, typewritten transcript, 1952 June 4; 43 pages.
  - Interview with Cooke by Frank H. Bartholomew, Sonoma, California, wire service copy and newspaper copies, 1948 November 21; Approximately 4 typed pages.
  - Interview with Cooke by Frank H. Bartholomew, typewritten transcript, 1954 May 16 and 25; 5 pages.
  - Interview with Cooke by Frank H. Bartholomew, Sonoma, California, carbon copy of typewritten transcript and wire service copy, 1958 October 13; 3 pages.
  - Interview with Cooke by Frank H. Bartholomew, Sonoma, California, carbon copy of typewritten wire service copy and wire service copy, 195? May 31; 3 pages.
  - Interview with Cooke by Charles R. Moore, Sonoma, California, wire service copies, 195? May 16; 3 pages.
  - Interview with Chiang Kai-shek by Charles M. Cooke, Taipei, Taiwan, multiple copies of typescript and carbon copy drafts, wire service copy, newspaper copy, and letter to Huang Shao-ku, Minister of Foreign Affairs, Republic of China, 1959 March 17, April 17; 6 pages.
  - Interview with Chiang Kai-shek by Charles M. Cooke, typescript draft with miscellaneous questions, undated; 10 pages.
  - "The Joint Chiefs of Staff. Why Always the Whipping Boy?," carbon copies of typescript draft, photocopies, and galley proof prepared for publication but not accepted, 1958 January 22; 6 pages. (Box 12)
  - "Keeping (the) Fleet at Sea," typescript drafts with carbon copies, undated; 2 pages.
  - Letters to editors, numerous typescript, carbon copy, and mimeograph letters, circa 1950-1964
  - "The Liberalisms of the Two Parties," typescript and carbon copy drafts, 1949 January; 16 pages.
  - "Lieutenant Commander Chen Runs the Gauntlet," typescript and carbon copy drafts, undated; 10 pages.
  - "The Line Officer Problem," United States Naval Institute Proceedings, Vol. 65, reprints, 1939 November; 12 pages (1587-1598).
  - "Marshall Island Attack," address to the National Executive Committee, American Legion, Washington, D.C., typewritten transcript, 1944 February 1; 9 pages.
  - Memorandum on the situation in China, prepared for James Fulton, U.S. House of Representatives, Committee on Foreign Affairs, carbon copy of typescript, 1948 March 28; 2 pages.
  - Memorial Day talk, Bubbling Well Cemetery, Shanghai, China, typewritten transcript, 1946 May 30; 6 pages.
  - "Naval Defense of the United States," address delivered to the Institute of Public Affairs, University of Virginia, mimeograph transcript, printed copies, and correspondence, 1940 June 15; 13 pages.
  - "Naval Strategy of the Far East," speech at the National Defense College, Taipei, Taiwan, mimeograph, 1953 December 18; 8 pages.
  - Navy Day address, carbon copy of typewritten transcript, undated; 10 pages.
  - Navy Day address, broadcast from U.S.S. S-47, Honolulu, Hawaii, carbon copies of typewritten transcript, 1931 October 27; 10 pages.
  - Navy Day address, typescript transcript, 1935; 9 pages.
  - Navy Day address, Portsmouth, Virginia, mimeograph transcripts and correspondence, 1943 October 27; 6 pages.
  - "The Navy--Pearl Harbor to the Philippines," remarks before the National Geographic Society meeting, Constitution Hall, Washington, D.C., mimeograph transcript and typescript transcript of entire program, 1944 November 17; 30 pages.
  - News dispatch on Russo-Chinese military alliance, published as a newspaper article, printed copy, 1950 February 17; 2 columns.
  - "Notes on Military Operations Required for Restoration of Freedom in East Asia and Western Pacific," memorandum prepared for Minister of Defense Yu Ta-Wei, Republic of China, carbon copy of typescript, 1960 May 28; 6 pages.
  - "Notes on the Advantages of Being Assigned to Line Officers Duties in the Navy Following Graduation from the Naval Academy," carbon copy of typescript, 1953 January 17; 10 pages.
  - "Notes on the Strategic Aspects of Crusade Against World Communist Aggression," carbon copies of typescript, undated; 10 pages.
  - "Organization of the Armed Services Establishments in Washington," comments and recommendations by Cooke, typescript and carbon copy drafts, circa 1953; 17 pages.
  - "Our Policies and Prospects in the Far East," speech delivered before The Economic Club of Detroit, Detroit, Michigan, carbon copy of typewritten transcript, mimeograph copies, printed copy, and reprints of speech as reproduced in Vital Speeches, 1949 September 26, December 15; 14 pages.
  - Outline of projected memoir subjects, typescript draft (incomplete), 1961 September; 9 pages.
  - "A Policy of Freedom," typescript and carbon copy article drafts, 1952; 21 pages.
  - Preceptorial on the Battle of the Philippines, made before Secretary of War Stimson, Assistant Secretary Gates, and Admiral King, typewritten transcript, circa 1940s; 21 pages. (Box 13)
  - Proposals for eliminating militant world communism, typescript, 1954 April 30; 2 pages.
  - "Quemoy: The Immediate Threat to Peace," Collier's, typescript draft entitled "Why Does the Kremlin Want Quemoy?," carbon copies of typescript drafts and revisions, correspondence, and reprints, 1955 October 14; 6 pages.
  - "The Relation of the China Situation to Possible World War," excerpts from a speech delivered to the Berkeley City Commons Club, carbon copies of typewritten transcript and typescript draft (incomplete), 1955 February 4; 9 pages.
  - "The Relationship Between French Policy and Strategy in the War of the Coalition, 1778-1783, and Its Lessons to Us," thesis submitted to the Department of Intelligence, Naval War College, typescript, 1934 February 1; 47 pages.
  - "The Relationship in War of Naval Strategy, Tactics, and Command, with Special Reference to Aircraft and Submarines," thesis submitted to the Department of Intelligence, Naval War College, typescript, 1934 May 7; 22 pages.
  - "Relationship of Military Preparedness to the National Policy and the National Interests of a Democracy," holograph draft, undated; 7 pages.
  - Review of The Conscience of a Conservative by Barry Goldwater, typescript and carbon copy drafts, 1960 May 6; 4 pages.
  - Review of Formosa by Joseph W. Ballentine, carbon copies, undated; 5 pages.
  - "The Road to Defeat?," carbon copies of typescript, 1960 October 24; 6 pages.
  - "The Road to Rehabilitation," typescript drafts (incomplete), 1959 June 15; 12 pages.
  - "Scraps of Paper," typescript drafts, 1958 April 7; 5 pages.
  - "Shanghai Destitute But People Welcome Nationalist Bombing," carbon copy of typescript, 1950 March 3; 4 pages.
  - "Should We Have a Single Department for Our Armed Forces?," remarks made in radio broadcast (America's Town Meeting), typewritten transcript and correspondence, 1945 November 15; 4 pages.
  - "Should We Recognize the Chinese Communist Government?," remarks made in radio broadcast (America's Town Meeting of the Air), typescript and carbon copy transcripts, mimeograph transcript, and printed transcript, 1949 December 6; 3 pages.
  - "Soldiers Need Wings: The Development of Ground-Air Forces," Foreign Affairs, Vol. 27, carbon copy of typescript draft and printed copies, 1949 July; 11 pages.
  - Solution to Hypothetical Operational Problem, submitted to the Naval War College, typescript, 1934 March 20; 28 pages.
  - Solution to Hypothetical Problem in International Law Concerning the Pact of Paris, August 1928, submitted to the Department of Intelligence, International Law, Naval War College, typescript, 1934 January; 36 pages.
  - Speech delivered on the occasion of the launching of the Timothy Pickering, Richmond Shipbuilding Corporation, Richmond, California, carbon copy of typewritten transcript, 1942 March 28; 9 pages.
  - Speech delivered to the officers and crew of the U.S.S. Pennsylvania, carbon copy of typescript and mimeograph, 1941 December 10; 1 page.
  - Speech to the graduating class, Tsingtao American High School, Tsingtao, China, typewritten transcript and correspondence, 1947 June 27; 4 pages.
  - Speech on the situation in Taiwan, typewritten transcripts, 1950 March 16; 13 pages.
  - Speech commemorating American independence, prepared for radio broadcast, Taipei, Taiwan, carbon copy of typewritten transcript, 1950 July 4; 2 pages.
  - Speech on combined military operations, delivered in MND (Ministry of National Defense, Taiwan -?), 1951 January 5
  - Speech on the situation in Taiwan, made in radio broadcast on the Voice of Free China, carbon copy of typewritten transcript, 1952 January 22; 6 pages.
  - Speech on Korea and East Asia, made in radio broadcast, typewritten transcripts, 1952 November 2; 7 pages.
  - Speeches on American foreign policy and military strategy, made in radio broadcasts ("Bob Siegrist and the News") in Wisconsin, mimeograph transcripts of remarks and question and answer sessions, 1957 August 28-30; 8 pages each.
  - Speech on conduct of military personnel while on shore leave, Shanghai, China, mimeograph transcript, circa 1946-1948; 6 pages. (Box 14)
  - Speech on Admiral Cooke's experiences in East Asia subsequent to World War II, typescript draft, undated; 11 pages.
  - Statement on the proposal for a unified command for the military services, delivered before the U.S. Senate, Committee on Military Affairs, mimeograph transcripts, 1945 November 8
    20 pages. Correspondence with W. Sterling Cole attached.
  - Statement on Reorganization Plan No. 6, delivered before the U.S. House of Representatives, Committee on Government Operations, carbon copy of typewritten transcript, undated; 9 pages.
  - "The Strategic Direction of World War II," lecture delivered at the Naval War College, mimeograph copies, carbon copies of typewritten transcripts, and typescript transcript (incomplete), 1952 December 16; 43 pages.
  - "Submarine Design," typescript and carbon copy drafts, undated; 5 pages.
  - "Taiwan - Citadel of Freedom," typescript and carbon copy drafts, undated; 9 pages.
  - Testimony before the U.S. Senate, Subcommittee to Investigate the Administration of the Internal Security Act and Other Internal Security Laws, mimeograph transcripts, correspondence, and news clippings, 1951 October 19; 22 pages.
  - Testimony to the Staff Conference of the U.S. Senate, Subcommittee to Investigate the Administration of the Internal Security Act and Other Internal Security Laws, mimeograph transcripts and printed copy, 1956 October 7; 9 pages.
  - "They Ran the Red Gauntlet on the Yangtze River," with Gene Coughlin, The American Weekly, printed copies, 3 pages [See: "Lieutenant Commander Chen Runs the Gauntlet"), 1951 November 25
  - "'Torch': The North African Campaign in 1942," typescript and carbon copy drafts, undated; 8 pages.
  - "U.S. War II Navy," typescript and carbon copy drafts, 1951 July 29; 4 pages.
  - "United States Relations with the Republic of China, 1945-1955," typescript draft, 1959; 91 pages.
  - "The Washington Story - The Job Ahead in the Japanese War," radio broadcast, typewritten transcript, 1945 May 13; 2 pages. (Box 15)
  - "We Planned It That Way," subsequently revised, mimeograph and carbon copies and correspondence with Walter Muir Whitehill, 1953; 50 pages.
  - "We Still Have a War to Win," radio broadcast, mimeograph, typescript, and carbon copy transcripts of remarks and question and answer session and news clippings, 1944 April 20; 12 pages.
  - "What Is Happening in East Asia," typescript and carbon copy drafts, 1952; 31 pages.
  - "What Will the World Be Like Thirty Years from Now?," carbon copy of typescript draft, 1934?; 4 pages.
  - "Witches Wool" ("Beggar's Velvet"), typescript and carbon copy drafts, circa 1932-1933; 5 pages.
  - Miscellaneous
    - Drafts and notes, incomplete and unidentified
      - Typescript and carbon copy
      - Holograph notebook
    - News clippings and wire service releases concerning the public statements of Cooke